# Ashish Kanwar

Software Engineer

	+1 514 546 3111
	ashishkanwar.com
	ashishthakur913@gmail.com
9	Montreal, Canada

#### SUMMARY

I love building new things from scratch and that is what I have been doing professionally for over 4 years. I am a tinkerer (DIY crafts, remote cars, LEGO) and that has always made me believe that I can build anything I desire. I am very passionate about writing code and bringing life-changing products to life. I am an outdoor person and I enjoy riding a bike or skiing downhill during winter.

#### SKILLS



### WORK EXPERIENCE

Art Of Where (Oct 2018 - Current)

Software Engineer

- Built a new website with react-redux for a new subsidiary company (artfabrics.com).
- Helped decouple a monolith into smaller, manageable composer packages.
- Develop and maintain a complex in house manufacturing management software. This software links most of the hardware/devices used for manufacturing, like printers and laser cutters.
- Increased code coverage by 10% using Codeception and Jest testing frameworks.
- Built an employee punch clock software using NFC tag reader-writer.

Classo.live (April 2020 - Ongoing)

Software Engineer

I am building this side project with my ex-colleagues. The platform helps individual instructors take their lessons online using video calling integrations like Agora and also manages payments for them. An MVP for this product is live at classo.live. We intend to make quick iterations and launch the product in coming months.

**Zomato** (Oct 2015 - Aug 2018)

Software Engineer

- Built Zomato's new product (Zomato Gold) contributing toward both tech and product development.
- Implemented PWA (Progressive Web App) for Zomato's mobile web in a small team of five.
- Implemented Google's AMP for Zomato's mobile web. This got featured on Google's blog post.
- Worked on Zomato's web platform frequently pushing new features live (front end and back end).
- Extensively worked on RESTful APIs for mobile apps (IOS / Android).
- Made various internal tools for the ad sales team helping the team derive more revenue.
- Worked on a product to detect real-time indoor location based on GPS and WiFi fingerprinting to provide location-based recommendations.
- Interviewed prospective employees and mentored junior software developers on the team

### **EDUCATION**

## Concordia University

(Sep 2018 - May 2020)

MS in Software Engineering

# Punjab Technical University

(Aug 2011 - July 2015)

BS in Computer Science